Jason J

Software Developer, Intellect Design Arena, Chennai, India

jasonj2698@gmail.com | +91 8754372649

https://linkedin.com/in/jason-j-2698-j

Summary

Front-end developer with 3+ years of experience in developing highly interactive web applications using **Angular (version 2 to latest version)**, NGRX, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Rest API. Seeking a role that allows me to utilize my expertise in software development, analytical, and problem-solving skills.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages JavaScript

Web Technologies/ Angular, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Ionic

Frameworks

IDE Visual Studio, Sublime Text
Tools MS-Office, Articulate Storyline

Database MongoDB Operating System Windows

Versioning Tools Git

Experience

Frontend Software Developer, Intellect Design Arena – April 2023 to till date Client: Saudi National Bank

Onsite Experience:

Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

Responsibilities:

- Working as a front-end developer (Angular)
- Developed web application using Micro Frontend application
- Developed mobile application using Ionic Framework
- Working with Saudi National Bank Team to enhance their financial sector, payments and bulk payments using Web Application.
- Involved in deployment process and mentored Junior team members.
- Involved in code review.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Angular 16, Ionic Framework

Digibyte Technologies Private Limited - Aug 2022 to April 2023 Client: Intellect Design Arena

Responsibilities:

• Responsible for Developing the Web Application using Angular 15.

- Analysed user requirements to develop software solutions and created technical specifications.
- Involved in code review.
- Analysed solutions and coding fixes for software problems.
- Provided technical support to customers regarding product usage and troubleshooting issues.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular15

Eazipoints System Private Limited - April 2021 to Aug 2022 Projects:

1. My Digi Force

Responsibilities:

- Worked with my Digi Force and Development Team to enhance their Signal Survey and Access Point Placements using Mobile and Web Application.
- Implemented signal survey and access point placement on Google Map using Google Map API.
- Responsible for developing the Web Application using Angular 11 to display their network survey maps and their detailed reports based on the signal survey results.
- Collaborate with back-end developers to implement and improve features.
- Implemented front-end solutions to meet project requirements for creation of user management.
- 2. Nokia Intuitive Survey and Planning

Responsibilities

- Worked with Nokia Research and Development team to enhance their signal survey access point using Mobile and Web Application.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure quality assurance throughout the development process.
- Created detailed design documents, test plans, user manuals, release notes and other related documentation.
- Tackled development tasks based on system requirements and documented approaches.
- Analysed code and corrected errors to optimize output.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, NodeJS, MongoDB

India CKP Hospitality Consultant – Nov 2019 to Feb 2020

Trained as Project Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Designing kitchen equipment in AutoCAD.
- Generating kitchen layout, MEP drawings and utility list, cost estimation.
- Understand the Design requirement and detailing in AutoCAD.

Internship

Orbio Solution Private Limited – Oct 2020 to March 2021

Internship Program on UI Development

Responsibilities:

- Designing and implementing web applications using HTML, CSS, Angular, Bootstrap.
- Contributed ideas during brainstorming sessions to generate creative solutions.
- Tested software applications prior to release and identified issues requiring resolution.
- Implemented enhancements that improved application functionality.

Education

- Completed BE (Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronic Engineering) on 2019 from Panimalar Institute of Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.
- Completed schooling on 2015 from Margoschis Higher secondary school, Nazareth, Tamil Nadu, India.

Additional Information

Name : Jason

Surname : Jebasuresh Samuel Raja

Date of Birth : 02-Jun-1998 Languages Known : English, Tamil.

Nationality : Indian Country : India